Billie Jean King: Hi, everyone!
مرحبا جميعا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thanks, Pat.
شكرا بات.
Thank you!
شكرا لكم!
Getting me all wound up, now!
أشعر الآن بالتوتر والقلق!
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Pat Mitchell: Good!
بات ميتشال: جيد!
You know, when I was watching the video again of the match,
أتعلمين، عندما كنت أشاهد فيديو المباراة مرة أخرى،
you must have felt like the fate of the world's women
لا بد أنك شعُرت أن مصير نساء العالم
was on every stroke you took.
كان مرتبطا بكل ضربة تسدّدينها من مضربك.
Were you feeling that?
هل أحسست بذلك؟
BJK: First of all, Bobby Riggs -- he was the former number one player,
بيلي جين: في البداية، بوبي ريغز-- كان اللاعب رقم واحد في العالم أنذاك،
he wasn't just some hacker, by the way.
بالمناسبة لم يكن مجرد متطفلٍ على اللعبة.
He was one of my heroes and I admired him.
كان قدوتي وكنت معجبة به.
And that's the reason I beat him, actually, because I respected him.
و لذلك قمت بهزيمته، لأنني أحترمه.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's true -- my mom and especially my dad always said:
هذه هي الحقيقة، دائما ما تقول لي أمي وخاصة أبي:
"Respect your opponent, and never underestimate them, ever."
"إحترمي خصمك، ولا تستخفي بقدراته أبدا."
And he was correct. He was absolutely correct.
و قد كان محقا، كان محقا تماما.
But I knew it was about social change.
لكني كنت أعرف أنه يقصد التغيير الاجتماعي.
And I was really nervous whenever we announced it,
و كنت أشعر بالتوتر كلما أعلنا عن ذلك،
and I felt like the whole world was on my shoulders.
وأحس أنني أحمل ثقل العالم كله على عاتقي.
And I thought, "If I lose, it's going to put women back 50 years, at least."
وتبادر إلى ذهني أنني إذا خسرت فسأعود بالنساء 50 سنة إلى الوراء على الأقل.
Title IX had just been passed the year before -- June 23, 1972.
وتم إقرار التعديل التاسع في العام السابق في 23 يونيو 1970
And women's professional tennis --
والتنس النسائي الاحترافي--
there were nine of us who signed a one-dollar contract in 1970 --
قام تسعة منا بتوقيع عقد بقيمة دولار واحد عام 1970--
now remember, the match is in '73.
تذكرت،انعقدت المباراة في عام 1973.
So we were only in our third year of having a tour
كنا في عامنا الثالث فقط من جولتنا
where we could actually play, have a place to compete and make a living.
حيث يمكننا اللعب، ولدينا مكان نتنافس فيه ونجني منه المال.
So there were nine of us that signed that one-dollar contract.
كنا تسع نساء قمن بالتوقيع على ذلك العقد بقيمة دولار واحد.
And our dream was for any girl, born any place in the world --
وكان حلمنا كأي فتاة في أي مكان في العالم--
if she was good enough --
إن كانت جيدة بما يكفي--
there would be a place for her to compete and for us to make a living.
أن يكون لها مكان للتنافس ولنا لكسب قوتنا.
Because before 1968, we made 14 dollars a day,
لأنه قبل 1968، كنا نجني 14 دولارا يوميا،
and we were under the control of organizations.
وكنا نخضع لسيطرة المنظمات.
So we really wanted to break away from that.
فكنا نريد الهروب من كل ذلك.
But we knew it wasn't really about our generation so much;
لكننا كنا نعلم أن الأمر لم يكن يتعلق بجيلنا كثيرا؛
we knew it was about the future generations.
علمنا أنه كان يتعلق بالأجيال القادمة.
We do stand on the shoulders of the people that came before us, there is no question.
نحن نعتمد على إنجازات الذين سبقونا وننتفع منها بلا شك.
But every generation has the chance to make it better.
ولكن يملك كل جيل فرصةً لتحسين ذلك.
That was really on my mind.
هذا ما كان يتبادر إليّ.
I really wanted to start matching the hearts and minds to Title IX.
أردت أن أربط العقول والقلوب بالتعديل التاسع.
Title IX, in case anybody doesn't know, which a lot of people probably don't,
بنص التعديل التاسع، في حال لا يعرفه البعض، وربما لا يعرفه الكثيرون،
said that any federal funds given to a high school, college or university,
على أن أي تمويل فدرالي ممنوح لمدرسة ثانوية، ومعهد أو جامعة،
either public or private,
سواء كانت عمومية أو خاصةً،
had to -- finally -- give equal monies to boys and girls.
يجب أن يقسم بالتساوي بين الجنسين.
And that changed everything.
وقد غيّر ذلك كل شيءٍ.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
but it's changing the hearts and minds to match up with it.
لكنه يغير القلوب والعقول لتستجيب له.
That's when it really rocks, totally.
ذلك هو الجزء المهم فعلا.
So that was on my mind.
و هذا ما كنت أفكر فيه.
I wanted to start that change in the hearts and minds.
أردت أن أبدأ بإحداث هذا التغيير في القلوب والعقول.
But two things came out of that match.
لكن هذا الاقتران ساهم في ظهور أمرين.
For women: self-confidence, empowerment.
بالنسبة للنساء، الثقة في النفس والإحساس بالقوة.
They actually had enough nerve to ask for a raise.
تجرأن على المطالبة بزيادات مالية.
Some women have waited 10, 15 years to ask.
في حين انتظرت بعض النساء 10 و15 سنة للقيام بذلك.
I said, "More importantly, did you get it?"
قلت" الأهم من ذلك، هل حصلتن على مرادكنّ؟"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And they did!
و قد نجحن في ذلك!
And for the men?
وماذا عن للرجال؟
A lot of the men today don't realize it,
يوجد الكثير من الرجال اليوم لا يدركون ذلك،
but if you're in your 50s, 60s or whatever, late 40s,
لكن إن كنتم في سنّ 50 و60 أو أيا كان، في أواخر الأربعين من العمر،
you're the first generation of men of the Women's Movement --
أنتم أول جيل من الرجال قد عاصر الحركة النسائية --
whether you like it or not!
سواء أعجبكم ذلك ام لا!
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And for the men,
وبالنسبة للرجال،
what happened for the men, they'd come up to me --
ما حدث للرجال، كانوا يقصدونني--
and most times, the men are the ones who have tears in their eyes,
غالبا ما تملؤ الدموع عيونهم،
it's very interesting.
هذا فعلا مثير للاهتمام.
They go, "Billie, I was very young when I saw that match,
يقولون "بيلي، كنت صغيرا لما شاهدت تلك المباراة،
and now I have a daughter.
و الأن لدي ابنة.
And I am so happy I saw that as a young man."
وأنا سعيد جدا لأنني شاهدت ذلك عندما كنت شابا."
And one of those young men, at 12 years old, was President Obama.
كان الرئيس أوباما واحدا من الذين شاهدوها في سن الثانية عشر.
And he actually told me that when I met him, he said:
لقد أخبرني بذلك لما قابلته، حيث قال لي:
"You don't realize it, but I saw that match at 12.
"قد لا تعرفين هذا، لكنني شاهدت المباراة لما كنت في سن 12.
And now I have two daughters,
و الأن لدي ابنتان،
and it has made a difference in how I raise them."
وأحدث ذلك فرقا في كيفية تربيتي لهما."
So both men and women got a lot out of it, but different things.
إذن استفاد كل من النساء والرجال من الأمر، ولكن بطريقة مختلفة.
PM: And now there are generations -- at least one or two --
بات": وتوجد الآن أجيال-- واحد أو اثنان على الأقل--
who have experienced the equality
قد جربوا معنى المساواة
that Title IX and other fights along the way made possible.
التي وفرها التعديل التاسع ونضالات أخرى.
And for women, there are generations who have also experienced teamwork.
وبالنسبة للنساء، توجد أجيال قد جربت العمل الجماعي.
They got to play team sports in a way they hadn't before.
أمكن لهن لعب رياضات جماعية بصفة غير مسبوقة.
So you had a legacy already built in terms of being an athlete,
إذن قمت بالفعل ببناء إرث كرياضية،
a legacy of the work you did to lobby for equal pay for women athletes
إرث من العمل قمت به للمطالبة بالمساواة في الأجور للنساء الرياضيات
and the Women's Sports Foundation.
والاتحاد النسائي للرياضة.
What now are you looking to accomplish
ما الذي تسعين لتحقيقه الآن
with The Billie Jean King Leadership Initiative?
من خلال مبادرة بيلي جين كينغ القيادية؟
BJK: I think it goes back to an epiphany I had at 12.
بيلي جين: أظن أن ذلك يعود إلى إدراكي للأمر لما كنت في 12.
At 11, I wanted to be the number one tennis player in the world,
كنت أريد أن أكون أفضل لاعبة تنس في العالم في سن 11،
and a friend had asked me to play and I said, "What's that?"
و طلب مني صديق اللعب فسألته "ما هذا؟"
Tennis was not in my family -- basketball was, other sports.
لم تكن عائلتي شغوفة بالتنس بل بكرة السلة، وألعاب رياضية أخرى.
Fast forward to 12 years old,
وبسرعة وفي سن 12--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
and I'm finally starting to play in tournaments
بدأت باللعب أخيرا في بطولات
where you get a ranking at the end of the year.
بحيث تحصل على ترتيب في أخر السنة.
So I was daydreaming at the Los Angeles Tennis Club,
فكانت تتملكني أحلام اليقظة في نادي لوس أنجلوس للتنس
and I started thinking about my sport and how tiny it was,
وبدأت أفكر بشأن رياضتي و كم كان مجالها ضيقا ومحدودا،
but also that everybody who played wore white shoes, white clothes,
و لكن أيضا كيف أن الجميع كانوا يرتدون أحذية وملابس بيضاء
played with white balls -- everybody who played was white.
يلعبون بكرات بيضاء-- كان الجميع محاطا بالأبيض.
And I said to myself, at 12 years old, "Where is everyone else?"
و قلت لنفسي وكنت حينها في 12 من عمري، "أين الأخرون؟"
And that just kept sticking in my brain.
وبقي ذلك عالقا في ذهني.
And that moment,
وفي تلك اللحظة،
I promised myself I'd fight for equal rights and opportunities
أخذت عهدا على نفسي بأن أكافح من أجل المساواة في الحقوق والفرص
for boys and girls, men and women, the rest of my life.
للجنسين، رجالا ونساءا، لبقية حياتي.
And that tennis, if I was fortunate enough to become number one --
وأن التنس، إن كنت محظوظة بما فيه الكفاية لأكون الأفضل في العالم--
and I knew, being a girl, it would be harder to have influence,
وعرفت أنه من الصعب أن يكون لدي تأثير لكوني أنثى،
already at that age --
في مثل ذلك العمر--
that I had this platform.
أنني أملك هذه المنبر.
And tennis is global.
ويعتبر التنس رياضةَ عالميةَ.
And I thought, "You know what?
وتبادر إليّ "أتعلمين؟
I've been given an opportunity that very few people have had."
لقد حصلت على فرصة نادرا ما تتاح للكثيرين."
I didn't know if I was going to make it -- this was only 12.
لم أعلم إن كنت سأنجح في ذلك -- كانت في سن 12.
I sure wanted it, but making it is a whole other discussion.
كنت أريد ذلك بكل تأكيد لكن تنفيذه أمر مختلف تماما.
I just remember I promised myself, and I really try to keep my word.
أتذكر فقط أنني أخذت عهدا على نفسي، وأحاول فعلا المحافظة على وعودي.
That's who I truly am, just fighting for people.
هذه أنا حقا، أُقاتل من أجل الناس.
And, unfortunately, women have had less.
وللأسف، حصلت النساء على القليل.
And we are considered less.
لازلنا نتلقى لأقل.
And so my attentions, where did they have to go?
إذن أين يجب أن أوجه انتباهي؟
It was just ... you have to.
كان الأمر أن عليك فعل ذلك .
And learn to stick up for yourself, hear your own voice.
تعلم الاعتماد على النفس، أنصت لنفسك ولصوتك.
You hear the same words keep coming out all the time,
تسمع نفس الكلمات يتردد طول الوقت،
and I got really lucky because I had an education.
وكنت محظوظة لأنني كنت متعلمة.
And I think if you can see it you can be it, you know?
وأعتقد أنه إذا جعلت الآخرين قدوتك، يمكنك أن تكون مثلهم،
If you can see it, you can be it.
إذا جعلت الآخرين قدوتك، يمكنك أن تكون ما تريد.
You look at Pat, you look at other leaders,
تنظر إلى بات والزعماء الأخرين،
you look at these speakers, look at yourself,
تنظر إلى كل هؤلاء المقدمين، انظر إلى نفسك،
because everyone --
لأن الجميع --
everyone --
الجميع --
can do something extraordinary.
يستطيع القيام بأمر مذهل.
Every single person.
كل شخص.
PM: And your story, Billie, has inspired so many women everywhere.
بات: ألهمت قصتك بيلي العديد من النساء في كل مكان.
Now with the Billie Jean King Leadership Initiative,
والآن بمبادرة بيلي جين كينغ القيادية،
you're taking on an even bigger cause.
تتبنين قضية أكبر.
Because one thing we hear a lot about is women taking their voice,
لأن الأمر الذي نسمع عنه كثيرا هو أن النساء يوظفن أصواتهن
working to find their way into leadership positions.
للوصول لأماكن قياديةٍ؟
But what you're talking about is even bigger than that.
لكن ما تتحدثين عنه أكبر حتى من ذلك.
It's inclusive leadership.
إنها قيادة شاملة وعامة.
And this is a generation that has grown up thinking more inclusively --
وهذا جيل نشأ وهو يفكر بشكل شاملٍ.--
BJK: Isn't it great? Look at the technology!
بيلي جين: أليس رائعا؟ انظر إلى التكنولوجيا!
It's amazing how it connects us all! It's about connection.
يعتبر ترابطنا معا أمرا رائعا! يتعلق كل شيءٍ بالترابط.
It's simply amazing what's possible because of it.
يعتبر المذهل ما يمكن فعله بفضلها.
But the Billie Jean King Leadership Initiative
لكن ترتكز مبادرة بيلي جين كينغ القيادية
is really about the workforce mostly, and trying to change it,
على القوة العاملة عموما، وتحاول تغييرها،
so people can actually go to work and be their authentic selves.
ليفتح المجال أمام الناس ليكونوا على طبيعتهم في مكان العمل.
Because most of us have two jobs:
لأن أغلبنا لديه عملان:
One, to fit in -- I'll give you a perfect example.
الأول هو الاندماج -- سأعطيك مثالا واضحا.
An African American woman gets up an hour earlier to go to work,
تنهض إمراءة أمريكية من أصول أفريقية قبل الوقت بساعة لتذهب إلى العمل،
straightens her hair in the bathroom,
تصفف شعرها في الحمام،
goes to the bathroom probably four, five, six times a day
قد تذهب إليه تقريبا 4 و5 و6 مرات يوميا.
to keep straightening her hair, to keep making sure she fits in.
لتحافظ على تسريحة شعرها. ولتتأكد أنها مناسبة لمكان عملها.
So she's working two jobs.
بالتالي تقوم بعملين.
She's got this other job, whatever that may be,
حصلت على العمل الاخر، أيا كان قد يكون،
but she's also trying to fit in.
لكنها تحاول الاندماج فيه أيضا.
Or this poor man who kept his diploma --
أو هذا المسكين الذي حافظ على شهادته --
he went to University of Michigan,
درس في جامعة ميتشتغان،
but he never would talk about his poverty as a youngster, ever --
لكن لم يتجرأ أبدا على الحديث عن الفقر الذي عاشه في صغيره، أبدا--
just would not mention it.
فقط لم يذكر ذلك.
So he made sure they saw he was well-educated.
حيث حرص أن يراه الجميع كإنسانٍ متعلمٍ.
And then you see a gay guy who has an NFL --
ثم تقابل هذا الشخص المثلي جنسيا وهو لاعب كرة القدم --
which means American football for all of you out there,
أقصد كرة القدم الأمريكية لمن لا يعرفها،
it's a big deal, it's very macho --
إنها مهمة جدا، و تعتبر رياضة قويةً --
and he talked about football all the time,
وكان يتكلم عن كرة القدم معظم الوقت،
because he was gay and he didn't want anybody to know.
لأنه مثلي ولم يرد أن يعرف أحد ذلك.
It just goes on and on.
و توجد العديد من الأمثلة.
So my wish for everyone is to be able to be their authentic self 24/7,
إذن ما أتمناه للجميع هو أن يكونوا على طبيعتهم دائما.
that would be the ultimate.
ذلك الهدف النهائي.
And we catch ourselves -- I mean, I catch myself to this day.
ونمسك بأنفسنا-- ما أعنيه، أقوم بذلك حتى هذا اليوم.
Even being gay I catch myself, you know, like,
حتى كوني مثلية، أتدارك بنفسي، مثل،
(Gasp)
أها!
a little uncomfortable, a little surge in my gut,
منزعجة قليلا، إحساس داخلي سيء،
feeling not totally comfortable in my own skin.
أشعر بالإنزعاج وعدم الراحة.
So, I think you have to ask yourself --
لذا، أظن أنه يجب أن تسأل نفسك --
I want people to be themselves, whatever that is, just let it be.
أريد الناس أن يكونوا على طبيعتهم، مهما كان الوضع، فقط كونوا كذلك.
PM: And the first research the Leadership Initiative did showed that,
بات: وأظهر أول بحث قامت به المبادرة القيادية،
that these examples you just used --
أن هذه الأمثلة التي ذكرتها --
that many of us have the problem of being authentic.
أن العديد منا يواجهون صعوبة في إظهار حقيقتهم.
But what you've just looked at is this millennial generation,
لكن ما تتطرقت إليه الآن هو جيل الألفية
who have benefited from all these equal opportunities --
الذي إستفاد من كل هذه الفرص المتكافئة --
which may not be equal but exist everywhere --
غير المتكافئة ربما لكنها موجودة في كل مكان --
BJK: First of all, I'm really lucky.
بيلي جين: في البداية أنا محظوظة فعلا.
Partnership with Teneo, a strategic company that's amazing.
تعتبر الشراكة مع TENEO، شركة إستراتيجية، أمرا مذهلا.
That's really the reason I'm able to do this.
هذا هو السبب الذي أتاح لي القيام بذلك.
I've had two times in my life
سنحت لي الفرصة مرتين في حياتي
where I've actually had men really behind me with power.
دعمني خلالهما رجال أعمالٍ أصحابُ نفوذ.
And that was in the old days with Philip Morris with Virginia Slims,
وكان ذلك في الايام الخوالي مع فيليب موريس وفرجينيا سليمز،
and this is the second time in my entire life.
وهذه هي المرة الثانية في حياتي كلها.
And then Deloitte.
ومن ثم ديلويت.
The one thing I wanted was data -- facts.
كل ما أردته كان المعلومات -- حقائق.
So Deloitte sent out a survey,
فقامت ديلويت بسبرٍ للأراء،
and over 4,000 people now have answered,
و شارك فيه أكثر من 4000 شخصٍ،
and we're continuing in the workplace.
وسنواصل ذلك في أماكن العمل.
And what do the millennials feel?
وما الذي يلاحظه جيل الألفية؟
Well, they feel a lot, but what they're so fantastic about is --
حسنا، هنالك العديد من الأمور، لكن الرائع بحق هو --
you know, our generation was like, "Oh, we're going to get representation."
أتعلمون، كان جيلنا يقول "أوه، سوف نحصل على شخصٍ يمثلك."
So if you walk into a room, you see everybody represented.
فلما تدخل إلى غرفة سترى أنه تم تمثيل الجميع.
That's not good enough anymore, which is so good!
هذا ليس كافيا الآن، وذلك أمر رائع!
So the millennials are fantastic; they want connection, engagement.
يعتبر جيل الألفية رائعا، يريدون التواصل والإرتباط.
They just want you to tell us what you're feeling, what you're thinking,
يريدون منك أنت تشاركهم أحاسيسك وما تفكر فيه.
and get into the solution.
وأن نصل إلى الحل.
They're problem-solvers,
هم بارعون في حل المشاكل.
and of course, you've got the information at your fingertips,
وبالتأكيد، فقد جعلت المعلومات في متناول يديك،
compared to when I was growing up.
مقارنة بالوقت الذي كنت فيه شابة.
PM: What did the research show you about millennials?
بات: ما الذي أظهرته لك البحوث بشأن جيل الألفية؟
Are they going to make a difference?
هل سيحدثون فارقا؟
Are they going to create a world where there is really an inclusive work force?
هل سيقومون ببناء عالم تكون فيه القوة العمل شاملة؟
BJK: Well, in 2025, 75 percent of the global workforce
بيلي جين: حسنا، في عام 2025، ستكون 75 بالمئة من القوة العاملة العالمية
is going to be millennials.
من جيل الألفية.
I think they are going to help solve problems.
أظن أنهم سيساعدون في حل المشاكل.
I think they have the wherewithal to do it.
أظن أنه ستكون لديهم الإمكانيات للقيام بذلك.
I know they care a lot.
أعلم أنهم يهتمون بالأمر كثيرا.
They have big ideas and they can make big things happen.
لديهم أفكار مهمة ويمكنهم تحقيق أشياء عظيمةٍ.
I want to stay in the now with the young people,
أريد البقاء مع الشباب ومواكبتهم،
I don't want to get behind.
لا أريد أن يتم تجاوزي.
(Laughter)
( ضحك)
PM: I don't think there's any chance!
بات: لا أظن أن ذلك ممكن!
But what you found out in the research about millennials
لكن ما توصلت لمعرفته عبر بحثك بخصوص جيل الألفية
is not really the experience that a lot of people have with millennials.
أنه لا يعكس تجارب العديدين مع هذا الجيل.
BJK: No, well, if we want to talk -- OK, I've been doing my little mini-survey.
بيلي جين: لا، حسنا، إذا أردنا التحدث -- حسنا، قمت دراسة مصغرة لفترة.
I've been talking to the Boomers, who are their bosses, and I go,
أتحدث إلى الكهول، الذين يعتبرون رؤسائهم، وسألتهم،
"What do you think about the millennials?"
"ما رأيكم في جيل الألفية؟"
And I'm pretty excited, like it's good,
أشعر بالحماس، وكأن هذا أمر جيد،
and they get this face --
وتتغير تعبير وجههم هكذا --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"Oh, you mean the 'Me' generation?"
" تعنين الجيل الأناني؟"
I say, "Do you really think so?
أجيبهم "هل هذا ما تظنون فعلا؟
Because I do think they care about the environment
لأنني أظن أنهم يهتمون بالبيئة
and all these things."
و كل هذه الأمور."
And they go, "Oh, Billie, they cannot focus."
فيقولون،"أوه، بيلي، لا يستطيعون التركيز."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
They actually have proven
لقد أثبتوا في الحقيقة
that the average focus for an 18-year-old is 37 seconds.
أن معدل الفترة التي يستطيع شاب بعمر 18 أن يركز فيها هي 37 ثانية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
They can't focus.
لا يمكنهم التركيز.
And they don't really care.
ولا يكترثون بشيء حقا.
I just heard a story the other night:
سمعت قصة في تلك الليلة"
a woman owns a gallery and she has these workers.
"تمتلك إمرأة معرضا فنيا ولديها عاملون.
She gets a text from one of the workers,
تلقت رسالةً نصية من أحد موظفيها،
like an intern, she's just starting -- she goes,
هي متدربة، بدأت العمل منذ فترة قصيرةٍ، وتقول الرسالة،
"Oh, by the way, I'm going to be late because I'm at the hairdresser's."
"أوه، بالمناسبة، سأتأخر لأنني في صالون التجميل."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So she arrives, and this boss says,
ولما وصلت، قالت لها رئيستها،
"What's going on?"
"ما الذي يجري؟"
And she says, "Oh, I was late, sorry, how's it going?"
فأجابتها، "أوه، لقد تأخرت، أسفة، كيف تجري الأمور؟"
She says, "Well, guess what? I'd like you leave, you're finished."
فكان رد الرئيسة، "حسنا، خمني ماذا؟ أريدك أن تغادري، أنت مطرودة."
She goes, "OK."
أجابتها الموظفة، "حسنا."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
No problem!
لا مشكلة!
PM: Now Billie, that story --
بات: الآن، بيلي، هذه القصة --
I know, but that's what scares the boomers --
أعرف، لكن هذا ما يخيف الكهول --
I'm just telling you -- so I think it's good for us to share.
أنا فقط أخبركم ذلك -- أظن أنه من الجيد أن نتقاسم هذا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
No, it is good for us to share,
لا، من الجيد أن نتشارك،
because we're our authentic selves and what we're really feeling,
لأننا نظهر حقيقتنا وما نشعر به،
so we've got to take it both ways, you know?
إذن يجب أن ننظر إلى الأمر من الجهتين، أتعلمون؟
But I have great faith because --
لكن عندي أمل كبير لأنه --
if you've been in sports like I have --
إن كنت جزءا من عالم الرياضة مثلي --
every generation gets better.
يتفوق كل جيل على سابقه.
It's a fact.
هذه الحقيقة.
With the Women's Sports Foundation being the advocates for Title IX still,
بمواصلة مؤسسة الرياضة النسائية الدفاع عن التعديل التاسع،
because we're trying to keep protecting the law,
لأننا نحاول أن نحمي القانون على الدوام،
because it's in a tenuous position always,
لأنه في موقف ضعيفٍ دائما،
so we really are concerned,
نحن فعلا متأهبون،
and we do a lot of research.
وقوم بالكثير من الدراسات والبحوث.
That's very important to us.
ذلك مهم جدا بالنسبة لنا.
And I want to hear from people.
و أريد أن أسمع تفاعلات الناس
But we really have to protect what Title IX stands for worldwide.
لكن علينا أن نحمي ما يمثله التعديل التاسع للعالم.
And you heard President Carter talk about how Title IX is protected.
وسمعتم حديث الرئيس كارتر عن كون التعديل التاسع محميا.
And do you know that every single lawsuit
أتعلمين أن كل قضية قانونية
that girls, at least in sports, have gone up against --
رفعتها النساء، على الأقل في المجال الرياضي --
whatever institutions --
وبغض النظر عن المؤسسات --
has won?
قد تم ربحها؟
Title IX is there to protect us.
التعديل التاسع موجود ليحمينا.
And it is amazing.
وأنه لأمر مدهش.
But we still have to get the hearts and minds --
لكن مازال علينا أن نجعل القلوب و العقول --
the hearts and minds to match the legislation is huge.
أن تجاري العقول والقلوب التشريع لأمر عظيم.
PM: So what gets you up every morning?
بات: ما الذي يحفزك كل يوم للنهوض؟
What keeps you sustaining your work,
ما الذي يدفعك لمواصلة العمل،
sustaining the fight for equality, extending it,
ومواصلة الكفاح من أجل المساواة، نشرها،
always exploring new areas, trying to find new ways ... ?
واكتشاف مجالات جديدة وإيجاد طرق جديدةٍ؟
BJK: Well, I always drove my parents crazy because I was always the curious one.
بيلي جين: حسنا، كنت دائما ما أثير جنون والدي لأنني كنت فضوليةً.
I'm highly motivated.
أنا متحفزة جدا.
My younger brother was a Major League Baseball player.
كان أخي الصغير لاعبا في دوري كرة القاعدة الرئيسي.
My poor parents did not care if we were any good.
كان والدانا الفقيران فلم يكترثا إن كنا جيدين أم لا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And we drove them crazy because we pushed,
وأثرنا غضبهما لأننا كنا نضغط على أنفسنا،
we pushed because we wanted to be the best.
قمنا بذلك لأننا أردنا أن نكون الأفضل.
And I think it's because of what I'm hearing today in TED talks.
وأظن أن السبب هو ما أسمعه اليوم في محادثات TED.
I think to listen to these different women,
أعتقد أن الإنصات لمختلف هؤلاء النساء،
to listen to different people,
أن الإنصات لأشخاص مختلفين،
to listen to President Carter -- 90 years old, by the way,
والاستماع إلى الرئيس كارتر – يبلغ 90 سنة، بالمناسبة،
and he we was throwing these figures out that I would never --
و كان يقدم هاته الإحصائيات التي لن أستطيع أبدا أن --
I'd have to go,
سيتوجب علي الذهاب،
"Excuse me, wait a minute, I need to get a list out of these figures."
"عفوا، انتظر قليلا، يجب أن أكتب كل هذه الأرقام في قائمة."
He was rattling off -- I mean, that's amazing, I'm sorry.
كان صاخبا-- أعني، هذا رائع، أسفة.
PM: He's an amazing man.
بات: هو رجل رائع.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
BJK: And then you're going to have President Mary Robinson,
بيلي جين: ثم سوف تتكلم الرئيسة ماري روبنسون
who's a former president --
الرئيسة السابقة --
Thank you, Irish! 62 percent! LGBTQ! Yes!
شكرا أيها الأيرلنديون، 62 بالمئة! الأقليات الجنسية! أجل!
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Congress is voting in June on same-sex marriage,
سيصوت الكونغرس في جوان على قانون يخص زواج المثليين،
so these are things that for some people are very hard to hear.
هذه أمور يصعب على بعض الناس سماعها.
But always remember, every one of us is an individual,
لكن تذكروا دائما، كل واحد منا هو فردٌ،
a human being with a beating heart,
إنسان يملك قلبا نابضا،
who cares and wants to live their authentic life.
يهتم ويريد عيش حياة حقيقية يريدها.
OK? You don't have to agree with somebody,
موافقون؟ ليس بضرورة أن تتفق مع أراء شخص ما،
but everyone has the opportunity.
لكن يملك الجميع فرصة للقيام بذلك.
I think we all have an obligation
أظن أننا جميعا مجبرون
to continue to keep moving the needle forward, always.
على مواصلة إحادث التغيير، دائما.
And these people have been so inspiring.
وهؤلاء الأشخاص كانوا مصدر إلهامٍ مهمّ.
Everyone matters.
الجميع له أهميته.
And every one of you is an influencer.
و كل واحد منكم لديه تأثيره.
You out there listening, out there in the world, plus the people here --
أنتم الذين تسمعونني، في كامل أنحاء العالم، إضافة للحاضرين هنا --
every single person's an influencer.
كل شخص يمكنه أن يؤثر على الآخرين.
Never, ever forget that. OK?
لا تنسوا هذا أبدا، فهمتم؟
So don't ever give up on yourself.
إذن لا تفقدو الأمل في تحسين أنفسكم.
PM: Billie, you have been an inspiration for us.
بات: بيلي، طالما كنتِ مصدر إلهامٍ لنا.
BJK: Thanks, Pat!
بيلي جين: شكرا بات!
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thanks, TED!
شكرا، TED!
Thanks a lot!
شكرا جزيلا!